A Guide to the Virginia Press Women Records, 1958-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Press Women Records, 1958-2007
The Library of Virginia
44098
5.65 cu. ft. (17 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Virginia Press Women, per Ms. Gwen Wolf, President, Fredericksburg, 23 January 2009.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Press Women was founded in 1958 and incorporated in 1973. It is affiliated with the National Federation of Press Women. The organization is open to women and men who are professionals in the field of communication, such as newspapers, magazines, radio, television, schools, colleges, government, communication businesses, and a variety of organizations and associations. The purpose of the organization is to promote journalism, exchange journalistic ideas, and offer continuing educational opportunities. The National Foundation of Press Women was founded in 1937 and had it's first meeting at the Chicago's Woman's Club.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1958-2007, of the Virginia Press Women and the National Federation of Press Women, including administrative records, brochures, directories, histories, minutes, newsletters, and photographs.
The Virginia Press Women is now known as the Virginia Professional Communicators.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Virginia Press Women, 1958-2007
Series II: National Federation of Press Women, 1968-2007
Contents List
- Series I: Virginia Press Women, 1958-2007., Extent: 14 boxes (4.6 cu. ft.). (Box 1-12a)
  Series I: Virginia Press Women, 1958-2007. This series includes administrative files, brochures, conference pamphlets, correspondence, directories, minutes, newsletters, and photographs. The administrative files were created as a catchall for a variety of binders that were arranged chronologically. The files include program notes, correspondence, reports, newsletters, clippings, announcements, lists of officers, conference programs, and emails. The conference files contain information on finances, program brochures, and registration; directories include bylaws and membership lists; included are histories written about the organization; and copies of the Leadership Manual outlining duties and events sponsored by the VPW. Of note are minutes, 1964-2007, of the Board and Membership committees; and the newsletter, Galley Pruf, 1962-2006.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Administrative files, 1958-1959. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative files, 1960-1962. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative files, 1963-1965. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative files, 1966-1979. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative files, 1980-1981. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative files, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative files, 1983-1989. (Box 1a, Folder 1-3)
  - Administrative files, 1988. (Box 1a, Folder 4)
  - Administrative files, 1989. (Box 1a, Folder 5)
  - Administrative files, 1990. (Box 1a, Folder 6)
  - Administrative files, 1991. (Box 1a, Folder 7)
  - Administrative files, 1992. (Box 1a, Folder 8)
  - Administrative files, 1993. (Box 1a, Folder 9)
  - Administrative files, 1994. (Box 1a, Folder 10)
  - Administrative files, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Administrative files, 1996. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Administrative files, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Administrative files, 1998. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Administrative files, 1999. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - A Time for Choices, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brochures, ca. 1980-1990. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Charter and Registration, 1959, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Conferences, 1997 April. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Conferences, 1997 September-December. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, 1998 September. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Conference brochures, 1977-2007. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Directories, 1977-1989. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Directories, 1990-1998. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Guide to Expertise at Virginia's Colleges and Universities and notes, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - High school writing contest, 1990-1993. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Historian reports, 1983-1993. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - History. (Box 4, Folder 3-3a)
  - Leadership manual, 1978-1994. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Logo. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1964-1968. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1969-1970. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1971-1972. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1973-1974. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1975 April 5. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1975 October 3-5. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1976 April 24. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1976 October 1-3. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1977 April 17. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1977 October 14-16. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1978 April 2. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1978 September 29-October 1. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1979 April 22. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1979 October 5-7. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1980 April 12. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1980 September 26. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1981 April 25. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1981 October 2-4. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1982 April 17. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1982 October 1-3. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1983 April 9. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1983 September 23-25. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1984 September 28-30. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1985 April 13. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1985 September 27-29. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1986 April 5. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1986 September 26-27. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1987 April 25. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1987 September 25-26. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1988 April 9. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1988 September 23-25. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1989 April 1. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1989 September 29-October 1. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1990 September 21. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1991 April 6. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1991 September 27. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1992 April 25. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1992 September 25. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1993 April 17. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1993 September 17. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1994 April 9. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1994 September 23. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1995 April 29. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1995 September 29. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1996 April 13. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1996 November 16. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1997 June 28. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1998 April 17-18. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1998 December 6. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 2000. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 2002. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 2004. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 2006. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2007. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1962. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1963. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1964. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1965. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1966. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1967. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1968. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1969. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1970. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1971. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1972. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1973. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1975. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1976. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1977. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1978. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1979. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1980. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1981. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1982. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1983. (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1984. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1987. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1991. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1995. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1996. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1997. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, Notes, 1997. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1998. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, Notes, 1998. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 1999. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, Notes, 1999. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2000. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, Notes, 2000. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2001. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2002. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2003. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Galley Pruf, 2006. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newsmaker of the Year, 1969-1992. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Oral history project, 1986. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Myrtle Barnes, 1983. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Agnes Cook, 1990. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Sarah Messer, 1984. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Louise Seals, 1990-1992. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Marge Solenberger. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Martha Steger, 1984. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Ulrich Troubetzkay, 1967-1969. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Melissa Wall, 1990. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Carolyn West, 1988-1990. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Past Presidents/Members, Miscellaneous, 1983-1997. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Women of Achievement/Woman of the Year, 1962-1996. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Photographs, ca. 1970-2003. (Box 12)
    Conferences, members, and speakers.
  - Scrapbook (oversize), 1960-1983. (Box 12a)
- Series II: National Federation of Press Women, 1968-2007., Extent: 3 boxes (1.05 cu. ft.). (Box 13-15)
  Series II: National Federation of Press Women, 1968-2007. This series brochures, conference files, directories, history, newsletters, and publications. Includes are brochures and programs regarding conferences and copies of the newsletters, "Agenda" and "Press Women."
  - Brochures, undated. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, 1987. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, 1991-1992. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, 1996. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, 2007. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Directories, 1996-1997. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Family literacy project, 1989-1991. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Governance and history, 2000-2001. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1990-1991. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1993. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1994. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1995. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1996. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1997. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 1998. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Agenda, 2000. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1968-1975. (Box 14, Folder 4a)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1977. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1978. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1979. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1981-1982. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1983. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1984. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1985-1986. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1987. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1988. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1989. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1990-1991. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1992-1993. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Press Women, 1994. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Publications, The Competitions, 1995. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Resource Book, 1993-1995. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Survey, 1995. (Box 15, Folder 11)